Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
=Rise of Her Lady Physician=
=صعود سيدتها الطبيبة=
=Episode 7=
=الحلقة 7=
=Drag Her Out and Beat Her to Death=
=اسحبها للخارج واضربها حتى الموت=
The silver needle and pine oil show no discoloration.
لا يظهر الإبرة الفضية وزيت الصنوبر أي تغير في اللون.
The Huoshan Dendrobium has no sulfur toxins.
لا يحتوي نبات Huoshan Dendrobium على سموم الكبريت.
- It really worked. - Rong Zelan
- لقد نجح الأمر حقًا. - رونغ زيلان
resolved the crisis
حل الأزمة
of damp medicinal herbs.
من الأعشاب الطبية الرطبة.
It worked!
لقد نجحت!
She really did it!
لقد فعلتها حقا!
Hurry, get the ingredients and prepare the medicine.
اسرعي، احضري المكونات وجهزي الدواء.
Deliver it to Consort Li.
تسليمها إلى الزوجة لي.
We have no time to waste.
ليس لدينا وقت لنضيعه.
That's wonderful.
هذا رائع.
Exactly.
بالضبط.
That's great.
هذا عظيم.
Feng Yin,
فنغ يين,
you framed your colleague out of jealousy
لقد اتهمت زميلك بدافع الغيرة
and damaged the herbs.
وألحق الضرر بالأعشاب.
As a medical attendant,
كمساعد طبي،
you disregard
أنت تتجاهل
the benevolence of a healer
إحسان المعالج
and violated the palace regulations.
وانتهكت لوائح القصر.
Do you admit your guilt?
هل تعترف بذنبك؟
I do.
أفعل.
Six months' salary deducted
تم خصم راتب ستة أشهر
and three days of confinement.
وثلاثة أيام من الحبس.
If you offend again,
إذا أخطأت مرة أخرى،
you'll be immediately expelled.
سيتم طردك على الفور.
I accept the punishment.
أقبل العقوبة.
I keep my word.
أنا أحافظ على كلمتي.
Starting today,
ابتداء من اليوم،
Rong Zelan
رونغ زيلان
is promoted to second-class medical attendant.
تمت ترقيته إلى مساعد طبي من الدرجة الثانية.
She's really promoted!
لقد تمت ترقيتها بالفعل!
- Thank you, Minister Wu. - That's great!
- شكرا لك، السيد الوزير وو. - هذا عظيم!
Uncle.
عم.
Useless!
عديم الفائدة!
Have you realized your mistake?
هل أدركت خطأك؟
Yes, Uncle.
نعم عمي.
I've realized my mistake.
لقد أدركت خطئي.
I shouldn't have underestimated her.
لا ينبغي لي أن أستهين بها.
The medicinal herbs were damaged,
لقد تضررت الأعشاب الطبية،
and you were punished.
وعوقبت.
What is her background?
ما هي خلفيتها؟
She is nothing but the lowly daughter of a demoted medical officer.
إنها ليست سوى ابنة متواضعة لضابط طبي تم تخفيض رتبته.
However, you were forced to kneel and beg for mercy.
لكنك أجبرت على الركوع والتوسل طلبا للرحمة.
Isn't that shameful?
أليس هذا مخجلاً؟
In the Imperial Medical Bureau,
في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري،
you either step on others' backs to climb up
إما أن تدوس على ظهور الآخرين لتتسلق
or wait to be crushed into mud.
أو انتظر حتى يتم سحقك في الطين.
You must earn
يجب عليك أن تكسب
our family's honor back.
شرف عائلتنا مرة أخرى.
Do you know what to do?
هل تعرف ماذا تفعل؟
I do.
أفعل.
Remember,
يتذكر،
you must secure the position
يجب عليك تأمين المنصب
of first-class medical attendant.
من مساعد طبي من الدرجة الأولى.
Rong Zelan.
رونغ زيلان.
She'll become a stumbling block in your path.
سوف تصبح حجر عثرة في طريقك.
You must get rid of her.
يجب عليك التخلص منها.
Make it clean.
اجعلها نظيفة.
Do not get our family into trouble.
لا تضع عائلتنا في المشاكل.
If you can't even deal with
إذا لم تتمكن حتى من التعامل مع
a minor medical attendant,
مساعد طبي صغير،
you'll be too incompetent
سوف تكون غير كفء للغاية
to stay in the Imperial Medical Bureau.
للإقامة في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري.
Go home and get married instead.
اذهب إلى منزلك وتزوج بدلا من ذلك.
Uncle, rest assured.
عمي، اطمئن.
I'll definitely use her lowly life
سأستخدم حياتها المتواضعة بالتأكيد
to secure our power
لتأمين قوتنا
in the Imperial Medical Bureau.
في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري.
Have you heard that
هل سمعت ذلك؟
the new officer is a prestigious family's heir?
الضابط الجديد هو وريث عائلة مرموقة؟
It's Officer Song, isn't it?
إنه الضابط سونغ، أليس كذلك؟
I've never seen him
لم أرى له مثيلا من قبل
diagnose a patient.
تشخيص المريض.
He wanders around the corridor all day.
يتجول في الممر طوال اليوم.
What kind of a physician is that?
ما هذا النوع من الطبيب؟
I heard
لقد سمعت
he has connections in the palace.
لديه علاقات في القصر.
How could such a worthless fool
كيف يمكن لمثل هذا الأحمق عديم القيمة
wear the physician's robe?
ارتداء رداء الطبيب؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
Attendant Rong.
المرافق رونغ.
What's the matter, Lord Song?
ما الأمر يا سيد سونغ؟
Congratulations on
مبروك على
your promotion.
ترقيتك.
Your meticulous calculations
حساباتك الدقيقة
have really intrigued me.
لقد أثار اهتمامي حقا.
At first,
في البداية،
I thought you were up to no good.
اعتقدت أنك كنت تفعل شيئًا سيئًا.
However, based on my observations these days,
ومع ذلك، بناءً على ملاحظاتي هذه الأيام،
I don't think you have ill intentions.
لا أعتقد أن لديك نوايا سيئة.
I can't help but wonder
لا أستطيع إلا أن أتساءل
why you're so eager to be promoted.
لماذا أنت حريص جدًا على الترقية؟
Now that you know I'm not a bad person,
الآن بعد أن عرفت أنني لست شخصًا سيئًا،
why ask further?
لماذا تسأل أكثر؟
However, Lord Song,
ومع ذلك، اللورد سونغ،
you don't know medicine
أنت لا تعرف الطب
but excel in martial arts.
لكنهم يتفوقون في الفنون القتالية.
You're unaware of Licorice,
أنت لا تعرف عن عرق السوس،
yet you frequently visit the Case Room.
ومع ذلك فإنك تزور غرفة القضية بشكل متكرر.
Even Minister Wu would show respect
حتى الوزير وو سيظهر الاحترام
when he meets you.
عندما يلتقيك.
I can't help
لا استطيع المساعدة
but wonder why.
لكن أتساءل لماذا.
Don't be nervous, Attendant Rong.
لا تكن متوترًا، أيها المرافق رونغ.
You resolved a crisis
لقد حللت أزمة
and saved the lives
وأنقذت الأرواح
of everyone in the Imperial Medical Bureau.
من كل فرد في المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري.
You don't seem to be a bad person.
لا يبدو أنك شخص سيء.
You saved me in the bathhouse
لقد انقذتني في الحمام
and lent me a helping hand in the herb crisis.
وأقرضتني يد المساعدة في أزمة الأعشاب.
I'll keep that in mind.
سأضع ذلك في الاعتبار.
Now that you know I harbor no ill intentions,
الآن بعد أن عرفت أنني لا أحمل أي نوايا سيئة،
I kindly ask you not to go further.
أرجو منك عدم الذهاب أبعد من ذلك.
If you continue to push me,
إذا واصلت دفعي،
I will take action to fight back.
سأتخذ الإجراءات اللازمة للرد.
Don't be so nervous.
لا تكن متوتراً جداً.
I'm just curious.
أنا فقط فضولي.
What's so special about the position of
ما هو الشيء المميز في هذا المنصب؟
first-class medical attendant
مساعد طبي من الدرجة الأولى
that you'd take such a risk?
أنك ستتخذ مثل هذه المخاطرة؟
My Lord, please
ربي من فضلك
put away your curiosity.
ضع فضولك جانبا.
If nothing else,
إذا لم يكن هناك شيء آخر،
I'll take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
Well, Rong Zelan,
حسنًا، رونغ زيلان،
let's wait and see.
دعونا ننتظر ونرى.
(I haven't eaten all day.)
(لم أتناول الطعام طيلة اليوم.)
(So hungry.)
(جائع جداً.)
(I wonder if there's any food)
(أتساءل عما إذا كان هناك أي طعام)
(in the Imperial Kitchen.)
(في المطبخ الإمبراطوري.)
Who? Who's there?
من؟ من هناك؟
(Imperial Kitchen)
(المطبخ الإمبراطوري)
(Coming to the Imperial Kitchen this late,)
(قادم إلى المطبخ الإمبراطوري في هذا الوقت المتأخر)
(is the person also hungry?)
(هل الشخص جائع أيضا؟)
(Imperial Kitchen)
(المطبخ الإمبراطوري)
(Could it be a palace maid)
(هل يمكن أن تكون خادمة القصر)
(sneaking in to steal food?)
(التسلل لسرقة الطعام؟)
(Imperial Medical Bureau)
(المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري)
Have you heard?
هل سمعت؟
Her Highness went missing last night
لقد اختفت صاحبة السمو الليلة الماضية
and was found in the Imperial Kitchen
وقد تم العثور عليها في المطبخ الإمبراطوري
devouring raw meat
التهام اللحوم النيئة
and even gulping down fresh blood!
وحتى ابتلاع الدماء الطازجة!
That's terrifying!
هذا مرعب!
And then?
وثم؟
Later, after she was sent back,
وفي وقت لاحق، بعد أن أُعيدت،
she got even worse
لقد أصبحت أسوأ
and acted like she was crazy,
وتصرفت وكأنها مجنونة،
shouting that she was hungry
تصرخ بأنها جائعة
and eating whatever she saw!
وتأكل كل ما رأت!
Paper, hair,
ورق، شعر،
candle...
شمعة...
She ate whatever she could get
لقد أكلت كل ما استطاعت الحصول عليه
without any hesitation,
بدون أي تردد،
and no one could stop it!
ولم يتمكن أحد من إيقافه!
Oh my goodness.
يا إلهي.
I heard that she's been
سمعت أنها كانت
afraid of drinking bitter medicine since childhood.
كان خائفًا من شرب الدواء المر منذ الصغر.
She keeps crying when taking medicine.
تستمر بالبكاء عند تناول الدواء.
The second-class attendant who prepared medicine for her
الخادم من الدرجة الثانية الذي أعد لها الدواء
was severely punished by Her Grace.
عوقبت بشدة من قبل صاحبة السمو.
Now all the second-class medical attendants
الآن جميع المساعدين الطبيين من الدرجة الثانية
are avoiding this task.
يتجنبون هذه المهمة.
It's more than just punishment.
إنه أكثر من مجرد عقاب.
Last month,
الشهر الماضي،
second-class attendant who prepared medicine for her
مرافق من الدرجة الثانية كان يعد لها الدواء
got 20 strokes from Her Grace
حصلت على 20 ضربة من صاحبة السمو
and was thrown out of the palace covered in blood.
وألقي خارج القصر وهو مغطى بالدماء.
She said that no matter
قالت أنه لا يهم
who prepares the medicine this time,
من الذي يقوم بإعداد الدواء هذه المرة؟
if Her Highness refuses to take it,
إذا رفضت صاحبة السمو أخذه،
she'll be beaten to death!
سيتم ضربها حتى الموت!
Luckily, we're not second-class attendants and don't
لحسن الحظ، نحن لسنا من الدرجة الثانية ولا نعتبر أنفسنا
need to prepare medicine.
بحاجة إلى تحضير الدواء.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
all second-class medical attendants
جميع المساعدين الطبيين من الدرجة الثانية
will lose their lives because of Her Highness.
سيفقدون حياتهم بسبب سموها.
Which second-class attendant can take on this task?
من هو الموظف من الدرجة الثانية الذي يمكنه القيام بهذه المهمة؟
Her Grace is urging us.
إن نعمتها تحثنا.
We have no time left!
لم يعد لدينا وقت!
(Rong Zelan,)
(رونغ زيلان)
(you asked for this.)
(لقد طلبت هذا.)
(There's no way you can escape this time.)
(لا توجد طريقة يمكنك من خلالها الهروب هذه المرة.)
Miss,
يفتقد،
Attendant Rong is exceptionally meticulous
المرافق رونغ دقيق للغاية
in her work.
في عملها.
Why don't you let her take on the task
لماذا لا تدعها تتولى المهمة؟
of preparing medicine?
من تحضير الدواء؟
- Oh, no! - Attendant Rong,
- أوه، لا! - المرافق رونغ،
take the prescription.
خذ الوصفة الطبية.
(Prescription)
(روشتة)
(Feng Yin,)
(فنغ يين،)
(no matter what tricks you play,)
(بغض النظر عن الحيل التي تلعبها)
(you won't stop me from becoming a first-class medical attendant.)
(لن تمنعني من أن أصبح مساعدًا طبيًا من الدرجة الأولى.)
(Princess Jinyi, Consort Li)
(الأميرة جينيي، القرينة لي)
Jinyi, my sweetheart.
جينيي حبيبتي.
Come on.
تعال.
Be a good girl.
كن فتاة جيدة.
Your Highness, please take the medicine.
صاحب السمو، من فضلك خذ الدواء.
Jinyi, come on,
جينيي، هيا.
take the medicine, and I'll
خذ الدواء، وسوف
give you the shadow puppet you've always wanted,
أعطيك دمية الظل التي أردتها دائمًا،
okay?
تمام؟
Come on.
تعال.
I don't want to!
انا لا اريد ذلك!
The medicine is too bitter!
الدواء مر للغاية!
I don't want to drink it!
لا أريد أن أشربه!
I don't want to!
انا لا اريد ذلك!
What is wrong with you all?
ما هو الخطأ معكم جميعا؟
Can't you even get the princess to take her medicine?
ألا تستطيع حتى أن تجعل الأميرة تتناول دوائها؟
You've been well fed and paid.
لقد تم إطعامك جيدًا ودفع لك أجرًا جيدًا.
Is disappointing me all you are capable of?
هل كل ما أنت قادر عليه هو أن تخيب ظني ؟
Your Grace, forgive me.
سيدي، سامحني.
I've repeatedly told the Imperial Medical Bureau
لقد أخبرت المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري مرارًا وتكرارًا
to make sure the medicine is not bitter!
للتأكد من أن الدواء ليس مرًا!
Why is the medicine still too bitter to drink?
لماذا لا يزال الدواء مرًا جدًا للشرب؟
Have you ever taken my words seriously?
هل أخذت كلامي على محمل الجد يوما؟
Do you think I am easy to fool?
هل تعتقد أنني من السهل خداعي؟
Your Grace, forgive me.
سيدي، سامحني.
Please give me another chance.
من فضلك أعطني فرصة أخرى.
I've given the Imperial Medical Bureau too many chances.
لقد أعطيت المكتب الطبي الإمبراطوري العديد من الفرص.
Someone, drag out the attendant who prepared the medicine
يا أحد، اسحب الموظف الذي أعد الدواء
and beat her to death!
وضربها حتى الموت!
Your Grace,
صاحب السمو،
please give me another chance!
من فضلك أعطني فرصة أخرى!
I'll definitely prepare something Her Highness will drink.
سأقوم بالتأكيد بإعداد شيء لتشربه سموها.
Why should I believe you?
لماذا يجب أن أصدقك؟
Your Grace,
صاحب السمو،
half a month ago,
منذ نصف شهر،
when I was reading the classics in the Imperial Pharmacy,
عندما كنت أقرأ الكتب الكلاسيكية في الصيدلية الإمبراطورية،
I discovered a method to help children take medicine
لقد اكتشفت طريقة لمساعدة الأطفال على تناول الدواء
in the historical records of the previous dynasty.
في السجلات التاريخية للسلالة السابقة.
I can't remember it clearly.
لا أستطيع أن أتذكر ذلك بوضوح.
I humbly request Your Grace to allow me to search for it.
أطلب بتواضع من سماحتك أن تسمح لي بالبحث عنه.
If it doesn't work,
إذا لم ينجح الأمر،
I'll accept any punishment.
سأقبل أي عقاب.
Okay, if she refuses to take the medicine,
حسنًا، إذا رفضت تناول الدواء،
I'll cut out your tongue!
سأقطع لسانك!
Thank you, Your Grace.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو.
I will not let you down.
لن أخذلك .
It's alright.
لا بأس.
Her Highness's illness is not ordinary.
مرض صاحبة السمو ليس عاديا.
She needs to take medicine,
إنها بحاجة إلى تناول الدواء.
but all medicine is bitter.
ولكن كل الدواء مر.
I got it.
حصلت عليه.
Have you heard?
هل سمعت؟
Rong Zelan was almost dragged away and beaten to death!
كاد رونغ زيلان أن يُسحب بعيدًا ويُضرب حتى الموت!
How is Zelan?
كيف حال زيلان؟
Is she okay?
هل هي بخير؟
Zelan!
كيف!
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Did you get hurt?
هل تعرضت للأذى؟
(Consort Li's got a fierce temper.)
(الزوجة لي لديها مزاج حاد.)
(How could she go easy on her?)
(كيف يمكنها أن تتعامل معها بلطف؟)
Attendant Rong,
المرافق رونغ،
why are you staring at me?
لماذا تحدق بي؟
Feng Yin,
فنغ يين,
stop pretending to be confused.
توقف عن التظاهر بالارتباك.
I know exactly
انا اعرف بالضبط
what you're up to.
ماذا تفعل؟
Attendant Rong, what do you mean?
السيد رونغ، ماذا تقصد؟
I really don't understand.
انا حقا لا أفهم.
What did you do?
ماذا فعلت؟
Attendant Feng, don't get me wrong.
السيد فينج، لا تفهمني خطأً.
I just saw some dust
لقد رأيت للتو بعض الغبار
and patted it off for you.
و ربتت عليه من أجلك.
They all saw it.
لقد رأوه جميعا.
It seems I got you wrong.
يبدو أنني أخطأت في حقك.
Attendant Feng, why do you look so pale?
السيد فينج، لماذا تبدو شاحبًا جدًا؟
Are you ill?
هل انت مريض؟
Maybe I can tell
ربما يمكنني أن أقول
Minister Wu you need a day off.
السيد الوزير وو، أنت بحاجة إلى يوم إجازة.
No need.
لا حاجة.
Yin, are you alright?
ين، هل أنت بخير؟
(Two Days Later)
(بعد يومين)
Attendant Feng,
المرافق فينج،
I heard Rong Zelan went to deliver medicine to Her Highness again.
I heard Rong Zelan went to deliver medicine to Her Highness again.
Her Grace was furious last time.
Her Grace was furious last time.
I'm sure she'll be punished.
I'm sure she'll be punished.
I wonder
انا اتعجب
if she can survive.
if she can survive.
(I had secretly added Coptis to the medicine.)
(I had secretly added Coptis to the medicine.)
(There's no way)
(There's no way)
(she can get lucky.)
(she can get lucky.)
Of course, I can survive.
Of course, I can survive.
Didn't Her Highness give you a hard time?
Didn't Her Highness give you a hard time?
Why would she?
Why would she?
Sort these herbs for me.
Sort these herbs for me.
(It's impossible.)
(It's impossible.)
(She must've played)
(She must've played)
(some nasty tricks.)
(some nasty tricks.)
(I must expose her!)
(I must expose her!)